MATTHIAS QUINN

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE



(330) 741-1068



miq_qedquinn@yahoo.com



Brunswick, OH 44212



GitHub

Executive Summary

I am an analytically minded <u>developer</u> who currently works remotely as a data scientist. I hold a Master of Science in mathematics with a specialization in statistics where I created software in Python for analyzing the validity of clustering models.

Experience

Feb 2023 – Present

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST

Progressive Insurance, Mayfield, OH

Lead architect of multiple production models to explain and make underwriting decisions.

Jul 2021 – Jan 2023

DATA ANALYST

Progressive Insurance, Mayfield, OH

- Utilized applied statistics to quantify project-specific effects on claims.
- Progenitor of department-wide API PoC.
- Reviewed large amounts of data across multiple sources to determine operational impacts and recommended actions.
- Developed and modelled internal metrics using SQL, Python, Tableau, and PowerBI.

Aug 2019 – Jul 2021

GRADUATE ASSISTANT

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH

- Provided walk-in tutoring for statistics courses at all levels at C.S.U.
- Utilized different teaching strategies to best assist student clientele.

Education

Dec 2021

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.S.) IN STATISTICS

GPA 3.95

Cleveland State University Cleveland, OH

Awards & Honors

Graduate Assistantship **Applied Predictive Modeling Cert**

Extracurricular Activities

Math Club Data Fest

May 2019

BACHELOR OF ARTS (B.A.) IN FINANCE

Cleveland State University Cleveland, OH

Awards & Honors

Dean's List

May 2020 – Jul 2020

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH

- Analyzed the ADD Health database.
- Created hierarchical / SEM models to identify at-risk youth.

Skills

Data Analysis

SQL

• Tableau

Python

• R

Snowflake

Statistical Learning

• Tableau

SAS

Publications

Explaining the school-to-prison pipeline via race and gender: The impact of trauma, school suspension, school dropout, and delinquency – Tedor, Mallett, Quinn, Quinn

Examining Trauma and Crime by Gender and Sexual Orientation among Youth: Findings from the Add Health National Longitudinal Study – Yun, Tedor, Mallett, Quinn, Quinn